Guide to the Jane Lathrop Stanford Papers SC0033B
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Correspondence, 1868-1905; Series 1; 6 Linear Feet
  - Incoming
    - Incoming: McIntyre, H. W., 1893 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - TLS Vina Ranch: Financial., Aug 6, 1893
      - TLS Vina Ranch: Financial., Aug 6, 1893
      - TLS Financial re. payment to Vina Ranch employees [with enclosures: McIntyre to C. Lathrop 1893 Aug. 15 and list of Vina employees and their salaries], Aug 22, 1893
      - TLS with statement re Vina employees, Sep 4 1893
      - TLS reassigning workers at Vina Ranch to pick grapes, Sep 5, 1893
      - TLS list of men sent into vineyards, Sep 5, 1893
    - Incoming: McKee, Mary Harrison, 1891-1894 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - ALS sends handkerchiefs and gloves, Undated
      - ALS Mrs. Hines leaving, undated
      - ALS accepts invitation for May 20 dinner, undated
      - ALS and cvr. accepts invitation, Apr 26, 1891
      - ALS and cvr. stay in California has been delightful, May 4, 1891
      - ALS accepts invitation, Mrs. Harrison at painting lesson, undated
      - ALS endorsement of Lucy Fletcher, Mar 17, 1892
      - ALS death of Mrs. Harrison, Jan 26, 1893
      - ALS enjoyed her stay at the University, April 15, 1894
    - Incoming: McNally, Father J. B., 1894-1895 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - ALS Feast of St. Aloysius day of L.Stanford's death, June 19, 1894
      - ALS religious discussion, Dec 27, 1894
      - ALS religious discussion, Apr 10, 1895
      - ALS mistaken idea that Leland Jr. was a baptised Catholic., Dec 30, 1895
    - Incoming: Mead, Larkin G., 1890-1901 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - ALS choice of marble for group statue, cost $8000, Dec 26, 1890
      - ALS condolences on death of Sen. Stanford, statue ready to be reproduced in marble, Jan 6, 1894
      - ALS hopes the family group in bronze arrived safely, 20-Dec-01
    - Incoming: Mills, Susan [President of Mills College], 1903-1904 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - ALS congratulations on Memorial Church, 1903-01-25
      - TLS would like a meeting to talk over educational ideas, June 1, 1904
      - TLS would like to talk about co-education, July 9, 1904
    - Incoming: Morrill family, 1891-1893 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Morrill, Justin S., ALS thanks for roses on 83rd birthday, Apr 19, 1893
      - Morrill, Ruth S. (Mrs. Justin), ALS social, Jan 3 1891
      - Morrill, Ruth S. (Mrs. Justin), thanks for flowers, Apr 5, 1893
      - Morrill, Ruth S. (Mrs. Justin), condolences, July 10, 1893
    - Incoming: Morton, Harriet M. (Mrs. J. M. Morton), 1893-1896 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - ALS season's greetings, condolences, Dec 30, 1893
      - ALS son in Pioneer Class, Dec 30, 1894
      - ALS season's greetings, news of her son, Jan 1896
      - congratulations, Feb 3 1896
    - Incoming: Murch, Chauncy, 1902-1904 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - TL re art works being shipped; reminiscences of his visit with her in Egypt, April 17, 1902
      - TLS saw that she was returning to Egypt, January 5, 1904
      - TLS thanks for the favor and good wishes for her journey, March 26, 1904
    - Incoming: McCana - McE, 1893-1902 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - McCana, Telephone message re. when to meet, 17-Jan-02
      - McClatchy, Mrs. James, Telegram congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
      - McClure, Margaret M., ALS social and personal notes, Nov 29, 1893 and Aug 28, 1895
      - McCoppin, Frank, ALS personal, May 23 [1893 or earlier]
      - McCoppin, Frank, ALS Letter of congratulations, July 1, 1895
      - McCudden, Jas. W., ALS congratulations, Mar 4, 1896
      - McCullough, Mary, ALS (4) congratulations and personal notes, Jan 17, 1895-Mar 4, 1896
      - McCullough, [?], ALS Congratulations, March 3, 1896
      - McElroy, Eliose, ALS appreciated visit to campus, Jul 14, 1894
      - McElroy, Wm. H., ALS appreciated visit to campus, Jul 1894
    - Incoming: McK - McN, 1883-1898 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - McKay, John, ALS Request for money, Aug 8, 1893
      - McKay, John, Tel. Congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
      - MacKay, John W., Tel. Congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
      - Mackay, John W., TLS re selling interests in Pacific Coast Railroads, February 12, 1898
      - MacKay, John [W.], ALS re: has not the time to visit University, Sep 18, 1898
      - Mackay, Louise Hungerford, ALS and cvr. introducing Lord Chesterfield, Feb 17, 1889
      - Mackay, Marie L., ALS re: making her "car" available to Stanfords in Paris, Nov 6, 1883
      - McKenna, Jim [?], ALS re legal matter, July 15, 1893
      - Mackenzie, Lydia A., ALS congratulations on court decision, undated
      - McKinstry, Laura Livingston, ALS congratulations on court decision, Mar 4, 1896
      - McLean, Emily Beale (Mrs. John R.), ALS and cvr. introducing Lord and Lady Randoph Churchill, undated
      - McLean, J.R., Tel. congratulations, Mar 2, 1896
      - McNeill, Mrs. K.M., ALS congratulations, personal news, Feb 9, 1896
    - Incoming: Ma, 1890-1899 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Madden, Jerome, ALS congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
      - Manderson, Charles F., ALS encloses dinner card on which he has written Pres. Harrison's toast to Gen. Sherman, May 15, 1890
      - Manning, A. W., ALS re donation of writings of E. Swedenborg to library, May 1, [1895] and May 26, 1895
      - Mansfield, Edith, ALS expresses her gratitude for year at Stanford, Dec 1, 1895
      - Marimott [?], F., TLS requests his bill be paid, July 12, 1893
      - Markham, Mary A., ALS thanking her for her kind letter, Sep 19, 1891
      - Martin, Father, Tel. congratulations, Mar 2, 1896
      - Martin, Mrs. Mabel, ALS re: Miss Minkler as companion, June 30, 1895
      - Martin, V.B., ALS will be offering mass for Leland and Leland Jr., Dec 17, 1890
      - [Matthews], Mary K., ALS congratulations, Mar 20, 1896
      - Maynard, Elizabeth P., ALS sending her two old letters, May 18, 1899
    - Incoming: Me - Mi, 1890-1901 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Merchant, R. H., ALS needs his papers back that he recently sent to Mr. Stanford, July 5, 1893
      - Metcalf, John W., ALS taught piano and harmony at Roble, gave 1st concert, Mar 5, 1896
      - Miller, E.W., ALS congratulations, Jun 30, 1895 and Mar 5, 1896
      - Miller, Mr. and Mrs. Frank, ALS congratulations, undated
      - Miller, Walter, ALS Leland Jr.'s collection arrived at museum, July 18, 1893
      - Milne, Robert Duncan, ALS re his memorial poem, July 17, 1893
      - Mitchell, Mrs. Alex, ALS congratulations on government suit, Aug 25 ny
    - Incoming: Mo - Mu, 1893-1902 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Moffat, Edmund J., ALS congratulations, Oct 13, 1895
      - Montgomery, W.R., ALS package received, May 26, 1896
      - [Morchetti], Ferdinando, ALS painted portrait of L. Stanford wants money or picture back, July 27
      - Morrison, Angela, ALS congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
      - Mortimer, John, ALS and poem "In Memoriam", Jan 18, 1894
      - Morton, Anne, ANS thank you, undated
      - Morton, Levi P., ALS unable to accept invitation, May 13
      - [Mott], Edward Marshall, ALS letter of support, Jan 27, 1896
      - Mott [?], L. C. [The Bancroft Company], ALS sending mourning paper, July 7, 1893
      - Mullan, R. W., ALS re opening of university, Oct 17 1891
      - Muller, Mary, Telegram announces a death, 19-Feb-02
      - Murray, E.N. et. al. (Stanford students in northwest), Tel. congratulations, Oct 15, 1895
      - Mutsu, M. (Japanese Legation), LS postpones dinner, undated
      - Mutsu, Riyo (Japanese Legation), LS and cvr. daughter has recovered, undated
    - Incoming: Nash, Herbert C., 1889-1902 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - Tel. re: L. Stanford's transportation to reception, Oct 23, 1889
      - Tel. and ALS storm at Santa Barbara; heard good news on legal suit, Mar 4, 1896
      - ALS Thanks for theater tickets, 21-Nov-01
      - ALS On his health, March 27, 1902
    - Incoming: Newman, 1893-1895 (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - Newman, A. E., ALS thanks for gift; religious thoughts, Dec 23, 1884
      - Newman, A. E., ALS expression of their friendship, 1893
      - Newman, A. E., ALS re travels, April 20, 1894
      - Newman, A. E., ALS travel news; religious thoughts, July 12, 1894
      - Newman, John P., ALS re exercise equipment he sent her, Mar 18, 1893
      - Newman, John P., ALS congratulations, wife with Mrs. Grant at Saratoga, Oct 14, 1895
      - Newman, John P., ALS congratulations, Mar 2, 1896
    - Incoming: Notre Dame Academy, Cincinnati, Ohio (Sister Lidgate), 1890-1891 (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - has left Washington for Cincinnati, Dec 20, 1890
      - sends satchel she has made, Feb 23, 1891
    - Incoming: Notre Dame Convent, San Jose, CA, 1894-1896 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Sister Bernardine, ALS Jennie happy at school, encloses poem by another Sister, 1894 Jan 15
      - Sister Bernardine, ALS thanks for RR pass, July 24, 1894
      - Sister Bernardine, ALS praises life in convent, 1894 July 22
      - Sister Bernardine, ALS news of Jennie, seasonal greetings, 1894 Dec 10
      - Sister Bernardine, ALS thanks for RR pass, Jan 4, 1895
      - Sister Bernardine, ALS re seeing Father Serra monument and efforts to build school in Monterey, 1895 Mar 11
      - Sister Bernardine, ALS sends prayer cards, Mar 16 1895
      - Sister Bernardine, congratulations on legal suit, July 1, 1895
      - Sister Mary of St. Teresa ALS Jennie wishes to be baptized, please advise, Jan 20, 1895
      - Sisters of Notre Dame, San Jose ALS Sister M. Bernardine gone east, Mar 5 1896
    - Incoming: Notre Dame Convent, Washington, DC, 1890-1891 (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Sister Clare, ALS personal, Dec 18, 1890
      - Sister Josephine of the B.S., ALS thank you, Dec 18, 1890
      - Sister Josephine of the B.S., ALS sends book chosen by Sister Clare, Dec 1890
      - ALS general thank you from convent, Dec 18, 1890
      - Sr. Josephine, thank you note for Sister Clare, Jan 5, 1891
      - Sr. Clare re: Madonna given by Stanfords; Sr. Josephine of the B.S. re: same and personal, Jan 23, 1891
      - Sr. Clare, L. Stanford's accident, Jan 29, 1891
      - Sr. Clare, Mar 7, 1891
      - Sr. Clare, asks about J.L.Stanford's birthday and addresses, Mar 12, 1891
      - Sr. Clare, ALS re own health, religious sentiments, Dec 14, 1893
    - Incoming: N, 1891-1898 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - National Council of Women, TL with ticket, program, subscription, souvenir etc.; circ. letter signed by Mary Lou Dickinson re Pioneer Reunion on 80th birthday of Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Oct 1895
      - Neimeyer, W.G., Tel. congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
      - Newcomer, A.G., ALS announcement of exercises for Founders' Day, Mar 4, 1896
      - Newcomer, A.G., typed poem to J.L.Stanford on her seventieth birthday, Aug 25, 1898
      - Nichols, William F., ALS congratulations, Mar 6, 1896
      - Nicholson, Watson et.al. (Stanford Club of Harvard), LS congratulations, Mar 14, 1896
      - Noble, Mr. and Mrs. John W., AL withdraw invitation because of death of Sec. of Treasury, Jan 31, 1891
      - Nordhoff, Lida, ALS personal news, Jan 2, 1894 and Dec 22, 1895
      - Notre Dame Convent, Columbus, Sister Lidwine, ALS Christmas greetings, appreciation for help given by Stanfords to the school in D.C. run by Sisters of Notre Dame, Dec 21, 1893?
    - Incoming: O, 1895-1902 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - [Ochellini], Thomas P., ALS congratulations, Mar 2, 1896
      - Ohara, Henlly Shoichi, ALS S.U. alum offers services during J.L.Stanford's visit to Japan, May 16, 1902
      - Olney, Richard, TLS Acknowledgement for receiving Stanford Quad, May 27, 1895
      - Olney, Richard, ANS social note, Dec 24
      - O'Neil, J. L., ALS will call on Monday morning, Mar 23
      - Osborne, Henry Z., Tel. congratulations, Mar 2, 1896
      - Owen, Mrs. J.J., ALS editor of "A Gallery of California Women" wants interview, Feb 12, 1896
    - Incoming: Pelton, J. C., 1895-1896 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - ALS congratulations, June 29, 1895
      - TLS congratulations, Mar 2, 1896
      - TLS reminiscences of Leland Stanford and praise for Jane, with typed poem, Mar 6, 1896
    - Incoming: Perkins, George C., 1896-1898 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Tel. re congratulations, Mar 2, 1896
      - TLS re: statue of Leland Stanford for Statuary Hall of National Capitol, encloses ALS Mar. 3, 1898 Justin S. Morrill to Geo. C. Perkins re same, Mar 11, 1898
    - Incoming: Phillips, Welton J., 1895-1896 (Box 8, Folder 4.1)
      - ALS wishes to see Mrs. Stanford, 1895 June 3
      - ALS expresses gratitude for her help, offers his to her in re government suit, 1895 June 11
      - ALS congratulations, 1895 June 29
      - ALS congratulations, 1896 Mar 2
    - Incoming: Pringle, Edward J., 1897 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - TL re: passage of bills for relief of University and fees, Jan 11, 1897
      - ALS re: his fees, Apr 27, 1897
      - signed receipt for fees, May 3, 1897
      - "revenge upon Gov. Budd", May 5, 1897
    - Incoming: Pa, 1888-1903 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Palmer, Burton M., Mar. 13, 1896; July 9, [1897] ALS, calling card and holograph poem "Victory" Mar. 1896 Park, Alma A.
      - Parker, Mrs. Julia, ALS including poems, Oct 28, 1893
      - Patten, Mary Elizabeth, ANS, Dec 5, 1888; Mar 1896
      - Patterson, Alma, ALS, May 23, 1895
      - Patton, Francis L., ALS invitation to Princeton, 5-Feb-02
    - Incoming: Pe, 1888-1903 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Peeler, Mary E., ALS sympathy, Jan 2, 1894
      - [Peers], Alexander, ALS, May 28, 1895
      - [Peet], R.B., ALS, Jul, 1895; Mar 7, 1896
      - [Pellet], K.A., ALS, July 10, 1893 and July 15, 1893
      - Penny, George Barlow, ALS with encl.: The Chimes of Lincoln Cathedral, July 25, 190[3]
      - Perkins, B. H., ALS request for money to help support his newspaper, Aug 7, 1893
      - Pettibone, W.H., ALS congratulations, July 10, 1895
    - Incoming: Ph - Po, 1890-1896 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - [Phelon, W.P.], ALS, July 2, 1895
      - Pierce, Margaret C., ALS, January 5, 1893
      - Pinkham, Dr. and Mrs., ALS congratulations on opening of university, Oct 12, 1891
      - Pittenger, Mary D [Poor Mary], TLS "America" copy of picture, Dec 27, 1893
      - Pittenger, Mary D [Poor Mary], TL, Dec 1894
      - Pixley, Mr. and Mrs. Frank M., AN on calling card, undated
      - Platt, Mrs. I.M., ALS daughter to be married, Mar, 1894
      - Pond, Mrs. A.L., invitation for Feb. 8, undated
      - Porter, David D., LS social regrets, May 12, 1890
      - Powers, Thos. L., ALS, Mar 9, 1896
    - Incoming: Pr - Pu, 1890-1902 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Pracht, Max (American Protective Tariff League), TLS with C.C. and pledge re: L. Stanford's signed pledge, Mar 11, 1896
      - [Prather], Mary E., ALS turn vineyards into raisin land, evils of wine, Feb 25, 1895
      - Preston, Harriet Waters, ALS to D.S. Jordan, Mar 3, 1896
      - Prior, Frank E., ALS thanks, Mar 9, 1895
      - Proctor, R., May 23, 1890 and July 15 1890 TLS and ALS
      - Pryor, Sara A., ALS (3), Jan 16-Mar 17, 1896
      - Puckett, Mary C., ALS with poem by her son, Jan 20, 1891
      - Putnam, Alfred, ALS, April 29, 1902
    - Incoming: Quayle, W. A., ALS, July 11, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Incoming: Reid, Elizabeth Mills and Whitelaw Reid, 1902-1903 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Reid, Elizabeth Mills, ALS Both social notes, Oct 21, 1902 and Feb 23, 1903
      - Reid, Whitelaw, TLS re appointment to Board of Trustees, 13-Oct-02
      - Reid, Whitelaw, TLS re documents for appointment, 21-Oct-02
      - Reid, Whitelaw, ALS re visit, memo, 30-Mar-03
      - Reid, Whitelaw, TL re letters received and sent, June 13, 1903
    - Incoming: Robertson, Mrs., 1892-1896 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      Stanford, Jane Lathrop; Stanford, Leland
      - ALS re: Mrs. Hewes illness, July 19, 1892
      - ALS sympathy, June 21, 1894
      - ALS sympathy, June 21, 1895
      - ALS congratulations, July 1, 1895
      - ALS congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
    - Incoming: Romer, Cecile, 1895-1896 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - ALS re their friendship and Romer's business affairs, [May?] 1895
      - ALS re ointment for horses, Nov 1895
      - ALS congratulations, Mar 2, 1896
    - Incoming: Ra - Re, 1893-1896 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Ramsey, Anne B. (Mrs. Wm. H.?), ALS (2) thank you, undated
      - Ramsey, Wm. H., Jr., ALS, Mar 4, 1896
      - Ramsey, Mr. and Mrs. Wm. H., Jr., ALS California visit from Port Washington, undated
      - Randall, H. F., ALS, Aug 1, 1893
      - Rawlins, James, ALS, Aug 30, 1893
      - Redding, ? [Mrs. Clements' nephew], ALS re. her dismissal from Roble Hall, Dec 31, 1896
      - Redstone, A. E., ALS, Aug 2, 1893
      - Reid, [S.?] L., ALS, undated
      - Requa, Mr. and Mrs., Tel., Mar 3, 1896
      - Retail Merchants Protective Assn. of Palo Alto et. al. (Tom Kemp), TLS, Mar 2, 1896
    - Incoming: Ri, 1893-1896 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Rich, A.G., ALS thanks for passes, Jan 18, 1895
      - Rich, Louise C., ALS thanks, etc., Jan 19, 1895
      - Richardson, Lucy S., ALS re the University, Oct 14, 1894
      - Riggs and Co., ALS, Aug 9, 1893 and Sep 1, 1893
      - Riggs, Kate G., ALS and cvr. sending poem by Mrs. Richard Lowell, Feb 1891
      - Riordan, W. O., ALS, Jan 4, 1895 and Mar 2, 1896
      - Riordan, Archbishop, Telegram Merry Christmas, undated
      - [Rixley or Riply], Mrs. M.F.W., ALS, Jan 27, 1896
    - Incoming: Ro - Ry, 1887-1902 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Roble Hall, card and cvr. congratulations, undated
      - Roe, Harriet W., ALS from niece of Dot Covert; death of Auntie Dot's husband Sept. 19, Sep 20, ny
      - Romero, Matias, ALS accepts invitation, Feb 23, 1887
      - [Rospigliosil] Marie Princess, ALS and cvr. estate built by Pope Clement IX, friends at London coronation, death of Mm. Di Cesnola, July 8, 1902
      - Ross, Mrs. Albert E., ANS congrats, Jul 2, 1895 and Mar 2, 1896
      - Ryan, E.B., ALS, Mar 3, 1896
    - Incoming: St. Joseph's Convent, Sacramento, CA (Sisters of Mercy), 1891-1896 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - ALS thanks for donation, signed by Sister M. Vincent, 1891 Nov 17
      - ALS sympathy on anniversary of her loss, signed by Sisters of Mercy, 1895 June 21
      - ALS welcome home, signed by Sister M. Liguori, 1896 Feb l0
      - ALS congratulations, signed by Sisters of Mercy, 1896 Mar 3
    - Incoming: Salisbury, Dr. J. W., 1893 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - ALS, May 11, 1893
      - ALS, May 15, 1893
      - ALS, May 23, 1893
      - ALS regarding Leland Stanford's health, undated
      - ANS (prescription), April 21, 1893
    - Incoming: Sartoris, Nellie Grant (daughter of Ulysses S. Grant), 1889-1902 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - AN thank you note, undated
      - ALS in mourning and cannot visit, Feb 15, 1889
      - ptd. wedding announcement for Vivien Sartoris, 23-Aug-02
      - ALS mother better Dr. Gardner, visit of J.L.Stanford, 28-Nov-02
    - Incoming: Smith, N. T., 1883-1895 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - ANS to J.S. Cone contract for purchase of Gerke Ranch, May 5, 1883
      - ALS personal, March 7, 1892
      - Tel. birthday greetings, Mar 9, 1893
      - ALS, July 27, 1893
      - ALS, Sep 23, 1893
      - ALS and T copy, Dec 23, 1893
      - ALS, June 29, 1895
      - Tel., Oct 12, 1895
    - Incoming: Speyer, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Speyer, James [Speyer and Co.], Jan 31, 1902 and Oct 17, 1902
      - Speyer and Co., [copies of telegrams], Feb 6, 1902; Feb 20, 1902; and Feb 21, 1902
      - Speyer and Co., ALS, 25-Nov-02
    - Incoming: Stanford, Helen (Mrs. Josiah Stanford), 1892-1895 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - ALS personal and family news, Joe building hay barn and fermenting cellar, etc., July 27, 1892
      - death of Anna, Aug 7, 1892
      - ALS inquires after Leland's health, Joe's been sick, May 7, 1893
      - ALS praises Jane's work with University, details her own financial difficulties, Sep 13, 1893
      - ALS regarding efforts on behalf of Mrs. Bigelow, November 26, [1893]
      - ALS worried for Jane's health, Dec 12, 1893
      - ALS, explains why she couldn't come to Menlo, June 19, 1895
      - sympathy for little Jennie, undated 1893?
    - Incoming: Stanford family, 1884-1901 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Stanford, Gertrude T., ALS, Oct 30, 1894 and Feb 6, 1896
      - Stanford, Jane Eliza (Mrs. Charles), ALS thanks, Jan 18, 1895
      - Stanford, Jeremiah, ALS Inquiring about possible relation to family, 15-Dec-01
      - Stanford, Josiah, ALS 1898 Resignation letter, May 31
      - Stanford, Leland, Tel. re. people to invite to dinner, Oct 20, 1884
      - Stanford, Philip W., Tel., Mar 2, 1896
    - Incoming: Stanton, Elizabeth Cady, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - ALS bird collection, June 20
      - ALS Woman's Bible, birthday celebration, 28-Nov
    - Incoming: Stewart, William M. (photocopies from originals at Nevada Historical Society), 1894-1895 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - TLS re government suit, with enclosure: letter signed by senators in support of J. L. Stanford, June 23, 1894
      - TL re. payment of debt to Mrs. Stanford, May 8, 1895
    - Incoming: Sa - Sc, 1889-1902 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - St. Joseph's Asylum, Wash. DC, Sister Euphrasia, ALS sorry J.L.Stanford can't visit orphanage [Orphan Boys of St. Joseph's Asylum]., Mar 30, 1892
      - St. Joseph's Asylum, Wash. DC, Sister Euphrasia, Poem to Mrs. Stanford, undated
      - [Samfisow], Emma, ALS, July 30, 1893
      - Savage [M.] J., ALS social, 29-Jan-02
      - Sawyer, Lorenzo S.B., ANS, Mar 3, 1896
      - Scanlon, P., ALS thanks for pass, Jan 4, 1894
      - Scanlon, P., congratulations, Mar 3 1896
      - Schlieffel[in?], Louise Shepard, ALS, Apr 23, 1893
      - Schliemam, Sophie, ALS death of husband, Jul 4, 1891
      - Schofield, J.M., ANS thanks for sympathy, Jan 4, 1889
      - Scott, Irving M., ALS, July 15, 1898
    - Incoming: Se - Shaw, 1893-1903 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - [Selal], Gregoire, ALS, March 7, 1903
      - Selby, Elena [Atherton], ALS, Mar 3, 1896
      - Seward, Olive Risley, ALS, cvr. and clip. condolence, death of father H.A. Risley, Sep 25, 1893
      - Sexton, [?] E., ALS, Mar 2, 1896
      - Shaen, Jacob, ANS, Mar 4, 1896
      - Sharp, Josephine, ALS personal news, husband on flagship of Pacific Squadron "Philadelphia", Nov 9, 1893
      - Shaw, Anna, Tel., Mar 5, 1896
      - Shaw, John W., Tel., Mar 2, 1896
      - Shaw, Julia A. (Mrs. W.H.), ALS sympathy, June 14, [1894?]
      - Shaw, Julia A. (Mrs. W.H.), ALS, June 20, 1895
    - Incoming: Shea - Sher, 1891-1904 (Box 8, Folder 27.1)
      - Sheasby, Mrs. Nellie, ALS, Mar 3, 1896
      - Sheehan, John F., ALS son a pioneer student at L.S.J.U., Jun 30, 1895 and Mar 2, 1896
      - Sheldon, Henry D. (pres. Associated Students), Tel., Oct 12, 1895 and Mar 2, 1896
      - Shephard, A. D., TLS, July 20, 1904
      - Shephard, Mrs. Vincent [L.], ALS [with enclosure], Feb 27, ny
      - Sheridan, Irene R. (Mrs. Philip), ANS thank you, Jan 7, ny
      - Sheridan, Irene R. (Mrs. Philip), accepts invitation, Feb 23, ny
      - Sherman, Cecilia S., ALS thank you, Bishop Newman, Mar 9, 1891
    - Incoming: Si - So, 1893-1904 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Simpson, Joseph Cairn, ALS, June 16, 1894 and January 1, 1895
      - Sloss, Leon, ALS, Mar 2, 1896
      - Sloss, Louis, Tel., Mar 2, 1896
      - Smith, Agnes, ALS congratulations, wants a loan, Mar 7, 1896
      - Smith, Mrs. Henry R., ALS congratulations, interest in kindergartens, daughter a Latin teacher, Mar 4, 1896
      - Smith, Joseph, ALS, July 30, 1904
      - Smith, S., ALS, Feb 28, 1896
      - Sommerfield, Kate, ALS Inquiry into Stanford admissions, 17-Dec-01
      - Soper[?], E. A., Tel., Aug 18, 1893
    - Incoming: Sta - Sti, 1891-1902 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Stafford, Walter A., ALS from Stanford student re. Government suit, Feb 24, 1896
      - Staples, Mary Winslow, ALS visit to L.S.J.U. with grandson now a student - Edward E. Painter, Dec 2, 1891